

# **Akshit Gandotra**

## **Student**

+919873316917

Dehradun, Uttarakhand

⊠ ga

gandotra.akshit@gmail.com

in Akshit Gandotra | LinkedIn

akshit-g (Akshit Gandotra)

2<sup>nd</sup> year Computer Science Major specializing in Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning. Interested in Natural language processing and Brain-Computer Interface. Creative thinker with strong analytical and observational skills equipped with excellent communication skills, work ethics, and a strong sense of leadership.

## **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

C/C++ Git **IBM Watson IBM Discovery** Chatbots Python Java **Prototyping** UI/UX Linux Applied Al HTML CSS Management **Problem Solving Decision Making** Community Outreach Resource Management

## ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

## Secondary School Certificate (Class X)

Apeejay School, Faridabad

2006 – 2019 Percentage: 93.5%

# Senior Secondary School Certificate (Class XII)

Modern Vidya Niketan, Aravali Hills

2019 - 2021 Percentage : 94.6%

# **Bachelor of Technology (Computer Science)**

University of Petroleum & Energy Studies

2021 - Present CGPA: 9.1

## WORK EXPERIENCE

### Web Design Intern

Dr. OP Bhalla Foundation (Manav Rachna University)

June 2022 – July 2022

Faridabad, Haryana IN

Worked to revamp and redesign the foundation website with increased focus on better user experience. Also worked as a mentor to the new batch of interns teaching them Figma and Adobe XD.

Also created a social initiative "Give her Wings to Fly", which included menstrual health awareness and sanitary napkin distribution. Initiated contact and collaborated with Unicharm-parent company of Sofy for the same

## **UI/UX Intern**

Road Safety Omni Foundation

June 2022 – July 2022

Faridabad, Haryana IN

Worked to revamp and redesign the foundation website with increased focus on better accessibility and modern design language. Worked to simplify and enhance the user flow. Changed the content of the site and worked as the content writer for the website team.

## Sub Executive (Technical Team)

National Service Scheme

September 2022 – Present

Dehradun, Uttarakhand IN

#### **Core Member**

Google Developer Student Club, UPES

August 2022 – Present

Dehradun, Uttarakhand IN

Managed and conducted multiple events across the AY. Was the speaker for the AI/ML bootcamp held under the Technova Annual Fest. Worked as event manager, designer, and editor for the GDSC club.

## **Event Head**

Association of Computing Machinery

April 2022 – July 2022

Dehradun, Uttarakhand IN

Conceptualized and managed multiple events while working with a team of 30+ members to successfully organize an event with a footfall of 500+ participants.

#### **CSR Mentor**

Sakshaar Hum Foundation

January 2022 – May 2022

Dehradun, Uttarakhand IN

Mentored a group of 10 students in the English Language who were associated with the NGO.

## **CERTIFICATES & COURSES**

Professional Certification in Applied Al

IBM (in association with Coursera)

May 2022

Python Project for AI & Application 
Development

IBM Skills Network (in association with Coursera)

May 2022

**Command Line Basics in Linux**

Coursera Project Network

May 2022

Python for Data Science, AI & Development

**IBM Skills Network** 

March 2022

Google (in association with Coursera)

In Progress

Introduction to Data Analysis using 

✓ Microsoft Excel

Coursera Project Network

May 2022

Building AI Applications with Watson APIs

**IBM Skills Network** 

May 2022

Google Cloud Essentials

Google Cloud Skills Boost

May 2022

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

Coursera Chatbot for students

Flask, IBM Watson, IBM Discovery

Guess the Number 2

Number guessing game

Python, GUI

**GUI Calculator** 

Python, GUI

ENG-FR Language Translator 🖸

Natural Language Translator

Flask, IBM Discovery, Speech-to-text

Madlibs Game

Python, GUI

## **LANGUAGES**

**English**Bilingual Proficiency

Hindi

Bilingual Proficiency

French

**Professional Proficiency**